WebPageTest is an advanced
performance analysis tool.
It's available at webpagetest.org,
it's free, and it traces how the
page loads and  gives back lots of
information in an easy to consume share.
Yeah, it looks a bit dated and it
could be too advanced at times, but
that's probably its only drawback,
and I really love it, otherwise.
And in this case, I'm going to use
WebPageTest to, and I'm going to
show you how to use WebPageTest,
to look at the loading waterfall
and figure out why CNN’s largest
contentful paint is so, well, large.
So in order to do that, what I'm going
to do is I'm going to go to WebPageTest.
I am already here.
I'm going to copy the  URL
of the page that we are going
to analyze and paste it here.
Then I'm going to change the browser
settings to Moto G 4, Chrome.
So, one thing I love about
WebPageTest is that it allows you
to test on real mobile device.
It's not just, not just simulated
mobile, like in Lighthouse, but,
or real, cheap, slow mobile phones.
And.
I'm also going to change the connection
settings to 4g,  to make it closer
to what PageSpeed Insights runs with.
And I'm going to start the test.
So, to save time, I'm not going
to  wait until the test finishes,
I already have a completed test.
And the test page has a lot of things, it
could be a bit  overwhelming initially,
but basically there are two pieces,
there are two kinds of information
I'm currently caring about here.
And the first piece is web vitals.
What PageSpeed Insight does, it
measures web vitals right on the device
we are doing the testing at, and in
this case we can see that, well, web
vitals measured at this Moto G4 phone,
actually, yeah, look not so good.
And the second piece that I'm currently
interested in is the network waterfall.
Network waterfall is waterfall of all
resources that are loaded over network.
And it's located right here.
It'spretty large.
CNN downloads quite a lot of stuff.
And I'm pretty sure most
of that  is third parties.
That's, like, it's
typically third parties.
And that's probably the reason
why total blocking time is
high, but we'll get to that.
Right now, we're talking about largest
contentful paint, so let’s focus on that