So, how do you check if this has
an effect, how do you check if
your server is actually slow?
This is easy to do both in
WebPageTest and in Chrome DevTools.
So in WebPageTest, you
have this huge waterfall.
So what you do is you click that
waterfall, you wait until it loads,
and in this enlarged format, in the
large shape and you scroll down and
you click on some network resources,
like say the index.html response.
This opens a dialogue with a detailed
information with like- actually one thing,
one thing that's great here is that a
lot of information here is not present
in Chrome DevTools, so if you are doing
advanced network debugging, this is
like super great and super convenient.
But yeah, this open a dialog with the
detailed information and there's a lot
of stuff here, but what we actually care
about is the time to first byte row.
Here it is.
And in this case, time to first
byte measured by WebPageTest
is 196 milliseconds, which
is actually pretty good.
And if you're in Chrome dev
tools, this is easy to do as well.
So what you do is you open the page,
then you open the browser dev tools.
You reload the page, you make sure you
have the network pane open, and once
resources start loading, you click on
any network resource, like, say, again,
index.html, you switched to the timing
tab, which is already open in my case.
And you look at the waiting
(time to first bite) value.
And in this case, the time to first
value is 40 milliseconds, which is even
better than what WebPageTest measured.
This is, this is really cool.
So yeah, in this case, both in
WebPageTest and in Chrome DevTools,
the time to first bite value is great.
In my experience, or in my opinion,
rather, I would say that any value
below 300 milliseconds is pretty good.
So in the CNN case, the server
slowness doesn't seem to be the issue.